Casas Adobes Rotary Club papers, 1976-2004
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Casas Adobes Rotary Club papers, 1976-2004
MS 428
Casas Adobes Rotary Club
Papers, 1976-2004 (bulk 1988-2002). This collection is comprised of the papers of the Casas Adobes Rotary Club. Items include organization files, photographs and negatives. The bulk of the material consists of Board of Directors information packets about the club's yearly activities which include meeting minutes, news bulletins, flyers for events, finances and member rosters. Also included are committee information and special event information as well as photographs of members and events.
2.50 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
The Casas Adobes Rotary Club was established in 1976 at the Cliff Manor Inn in Tucson, Arizona. The club began as the Northside Breakfast Club and a Rotary charter was issued in November of that year making it the 17,018th Rotary club in the world. Tucson established its first Rotary club, the Downtown Club, in 1921. As Tucson grew, additional clubs were formed in Tucson including the Casas Adobes Rotary. In 1985 the club moved to Westward Look due to the increase in membership. The club participated in a variety of fund raising projects for charity and education. They created a non-profit foundation to receive and distribute funds to these projects. The club is a service oriented club and participates in service projects beyond the charities and scholarships it supports. Casas Adobes Rotary club has a sister club relationship with the Rotary Club of Hermosillo-Pitic in Sonora, Mexico.
Organization
This collection is organized into 2 series:
Series 1: Organization Files, 1976-2004
Series 2: Photographs and Negatives, 1986-2001
Scope and Content Note
Papers, 1976-2004 (bulk 1988-2002). This collection contains the papers of the Casas Adobes Rotary Club documenting the organization in Tucson. The bulk of the material is information prepared for the Board of Directors containing meeting minutes, news bulletins, meeting attendees, club activities, finances and other information related to the club. Also included are committee packets, member rosters and photographs and negatives of club events and members.
Access Terms
Rotary Club of Tucson (Casas Adobes)-- Archive
Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States
Charities -- Arizona -- Tucson
Container List
- Series 1: Organization Files, 1976-2004
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains documents related to the club including Board of Director meetings, new bulletins, special committee information and other club information including events and pamphlets.
  - Board of Directors. 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors. 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Board of Directors. 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
  - Board of Directors. 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
  - Board of Directors. 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Board of Directors. 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Board of Directors. 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Board of Directors. 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Board of Directors. 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors. 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Board of Directors. 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Board of Directors. 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Board of Directors- Bulletins. 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Board of Directors- Bulletins. 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors- Polio Plus Campaign. 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors- Team Member Selection Committee, Japan. 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors- Tucson Council for International Visitors. 1985-2004 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Events. 2000-2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - General. 1998 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Informational pamphlets. undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - International Committee. 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Roster. 1987-1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Roster. 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
- Series 2: Photographs and Negatives, 1986-2001
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains photographs of club members and events including charity projects, scholarship banquets and sister club meetings.
  - Photographs- Board of Directors. 1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Photographs- Christmas in April. undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Photographs- Events. 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Photographs- General. undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Photographs- Hermosillo Rotary. 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Photographs- Honor Roll Breakfast. undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Photographs- Members. undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Photographs- YMCA work project. 2001 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Negatives- Honor Roll Breakfast. undated (Box 3, Folder 12)